Creative Full-stack Developer focusing on Front-end with 4+ years of experience providing high-impact web applications for diverse industry organizations. Skilled in design, animation, development and testing multiple web-based apps incorporating a range of technologies. Aspiring to combine experience with strong technical and managerial skills to excel as Full-stack Developer.

#### **EDUCATION**

**B.Tech Computer Science**, Cochin University of Science and Technology Jul 2018 - Jul 2022 | Kochi, India

#### **CGPA: 8.45**

- Chairman, IEEE Computer Society.
- Co-lead, Google Developer Students Club.
- Head of Technology, TEDxCUSAT.

#### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

**Software Engineering Intern,** Open Water Accelerator ☑

Sep 2020 - Dec 2020 | Menlo Park, CA, US

## Responsibilities: UI Design, Development, unit testing and documentation.

- Reduced analysis time for Enterprise clients by 30% implementing Maps Analytics Dashboard using Mapbox API, React and Django.
- Improved performance by 20% by fixing application-wide bugs and refactoring code.
- Liaised with back end, front end developers, quality assurance testers, and managers as needed.

**Design & Development Intern,** Hapiens Digital Pvt Ltd.

Nov 2019 - Mar 2020 | Kochi, India

# Responsibilities: UI/UX Design and Fullstack Development.

- Improved company productivity by automating messaging in Telegram group.
- Automated and scaled complex manual company tasks and workflows.
- Collaborated with the team, participated in meetings and presented innovative
- Tested, debugged and improved code which drastically improved performance.

### UI/UX Research Intern, CodeSteak LLP ☑

Jun 2019 | Kochi, India

Responsibilities: UI Design and prototyping.

- Designed User Interfaces and prototypes for client websites.
- Collaborated with the team and presented well planned and scalable designs.
- Revamped existing designs and experiences which improved user experience.

# **LEADERSHIP POSITIONS & VOLUNTEERING**

**IEEE Computer Society** (Chairman) | **TEDxCUSAT** (Head of Tech)

Facebook Developer Circles, Kochi (Lead of Design and Tech)

**Google Developers Group, Cochin (Organizer)** 

**Google Developer Student Clubs (Co-Lead)** 

TinkerHub Foundation (Core Member)

**Dhishna Techfest** (Head of Design & Media.)

Make-A-Ton (Tech Lead & Organizer)

Innovators' Summit (Head of Media & Organizer)

#### **SKILLS**

Soft Skills (Problem Solving, Leadership, Multitasking, Programming, Networking, Communication, Teamwork.)

**Development Skills** (Javascript, Python, React.js, Node.js, Git, Three.js, SQL, MongoDB, Firebase.)

Design Skills (UI Design, UI prototyping, Adobe XD, Framer, Figma, Invision, After Effects.)

# **PROJECTS**

**Google Cloud Ready Facilitator Dashboard,** This Application automates the 2+ hrs of Daily manual student report generation of GCR facilitator.

**Graphs Visualizer,** A Visualizer that allows you to draw directed graphs and shows the corresponding matrices. Visualization of various algorithms are to be implemented in future releases. ☑

## Daily Messages Telegram Scheduler, A

Telegram Bot that posts scheduled messages. The messages which include images with caption and custom message is stored in MongoDB. This is managed on a Express.js Server in Node.js. ♂

## **Doctor Patient Record System, A**

doctor-patient management system. Doctors can add prescription and medical history. Patients can view their medical progress. 🛮

**RefractionX Simulation, Interactive** physics simulation on refraction made using Javascrpit and HTML+CSS.

# **ACHIEVEMENTS**

### Top 3 Projects,

Open Water Accelerator Hackathon

Selected for InOut 6.0 Hackathon from a pool of 1000s of Nation-wide applicants.

Top Contributor, Code4Munnar